Kwame Adaboh

I am a software developer with 4 years of experience specializing in web technologies and full-stack application development. Throughout my career, I have worked on diverse projects, serving clients in both the public and private sectors.

EXPERIENCE

BK. Grand Technologies Ltd, Accra — Software Developer

July 2019 - PRESENT

Worked as a junior developer on various government and private sector projects. Most notably was part of the development team for CSSPS, a yearly government program used to place basic school students in public second-cycle institutions. Helped build and deploy a management platform for government employees to help supervise and coordinate the placement process.

National Information Technology Agency (NITA) — Researcher

Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

Worked as a researcher for NITA's standardization department, helping to devise policies for the regulation of Ghana's ICT environment.

Twelve Springs Investment Group, Accra — *Junior Developer* (*ReactJS*)

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

Worked as a web developer on Expertly Global, a platform for experts to provide live masterclasses to interested participants. Used ReactJS, NodeJS, and Neo4j during the application-building process. I also gained familiarity with WebRTC technologies, such as Jitsi and Vonage.

Moonsquare LTD, Accra — Front-End Tech Lead, Jobs and Skills Project (ReactJS)

April 2021 - Present

Currently work primarily as the Front-End Tech Lead for the Ghana Jobs and Skills Project, a World Bank-funded initiative. In this role, I provided technical leadership and guided the implementation of the project. Collaborating with a skilled team, we built intuitive interfaces and facilitated seamless interactions between job seekers, employers, and skill-building resources. The project, utilized by the Ministry of Finance, aimed to address the critical challenges of job search and skills development.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/kwame-ada boh-9a3b2b18a

SKILLS

Web Development (ReactJS, TypeScript, HTML, Node)

Software Development

Augmented Reality

Mobile Development (React-Native)

Machine Learning (Tensorflow)

AWARDS

Best Graduating Computer Science Student, Valley View University (2021) During the initial rollout, the Ghana Jobs and Skills Project attracted about 300,000 applicants. These individuals successfully utilized the platform to access job opportunities and skill-building resources. These applicants have effectively transitioned to other aspects of the initiative, indicating the positive impact and engagement of the project.

EDUCATION

Valley View University, Accra — Bsc. Computer Science

lan 2017 - Dec 2021

- Graduated with First Class Honors.
- Was awarded as the Best Computer Science student in graduating class.

SIDE PROJECTS

Illegal Mining Detection (Tensorflow/ReactJS) — *Jun* 2021 – *Present*

Ghana faces a significant environmental crisis due to illegal mining. I built a convolutional neural network to detect illegal mining from high spatial resolution satellite photography. Currently researching how this solution could be scaled up to track and curtail the spread of illegal mining in the country.

Built ARGUS, a proof-of-concept web application to aid in demonstrating, testing, and improving the model.

bit.ly/kwame121

LibrARy (React Native) — Jun 2022 - Present

LibrARy is an Edu–Tech app designed to provide African students with valuable study material using Augmented Reality (AR). By harnessing the power of AR technology, the app offers students an immersive and interactive learning experience. It serves as a virtual library, delivering insightful content that enhances their understanding of various subjects. With LibrARy, African students can access a wealth of educational resources and gain a deeper understanding of their study material, empowering them to excel in their academic pursuits.

Demos of LibrARy can be found here.

https://www.instagram.com/stories/highlights/18006801169708065/

- **Prince Yaw Amoako** Lecturer, Valley View University papaprince@vvu.edu.gh
- **Prof. Dominic D. Damoah** Lecturer, Valley View University kwddamoah@vvu.edu.gh
- Paul Kwaku Kyei Ofori Deputy Director General, National Council for Curriculum and Assessment
 - o <u>pko5@georgetown.edu</u>